

M.UMAR MUZAFFAR

@MUmarMuzaffar in .com/in/mumarm f.me/muhammadumarmuzaffar

mumarm@outlook.com

4 +92 (345) 244 8919

Clifton, Karachi

Google Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

HubSpot Social Media Marketing Certificate



Linked in Online Marketing Foundations

Digital Marketer Marketing Strategist

A writer at heart and marketer by profession. I'm a business graduate with demonstrated experience in strategy, management & communications.

Skilled in Copywriting, Market Research, Marketing Strategy, Digital Marketing, Business Development, Brand Management & Customer Relations.

Creative individual & eager student of Social Sciences with Master's degree in Economics from University of Karachi & MBA with research study in Islamic

Marketing. QUALIFICATIONS

- Copywriting
- Brand Management
- Marketing Strategy
- Digital Marketing
- Client Relations

SOFT SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Positive Attitude
- Communication
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving

KEY COURSES

- Business, Brand and Behaviour (London Business
- Google Analytics Individual Qualification
- Google Fundamentals of **Digital Marketing**
- Hubspot Social Media Certification
- Presentation Skills Course (2010) - TSA
- Intensive Conversation Course (2005) - PACC

EXPERIENCE

Currently freelancing online as Digital & Marketing Strategist

MARKETING CONSULTANT

WashnClean.pk | Jan 2018 - June 2018

WASHOCLEAN

- Established Brand Guidelines
- Conducted Logo redesign (Credit: Fahad Hayat)
- Developed brand assets & company profile
- Executed Digital Marketing
- Established & Managed Social Media channels
- Verified Digital Business Listing (GoogleMyBusiness)
- Website Copy & Content Writing

ASSISTANT MARKETING MANAGER

Tech4Life Enterprises | Dec 2016 - Nov 2017

Digital Health & Tele-medicine Firm





- Developed Marketing collateral & campaigns in coordination with Advertising agencies as per brand guidelines
- Digital Marketing (Social Media Marketing, Search Engine Optimization & SE Marketing)
- Prepared Value Creation plan for Product Management
- Managed Cross-functional teams to ensure successful implementation of strategic plans
- Established & managed a global distribution network & enabled large-scale local implementation (South Asia, MENA & Europe)
- · Successfully registered product with regulatory bodies: CE Certification, Pakistan Chemists & Druggists Association & Drug Regulatory Authority of Pakistan
- Successfully conducted Customs clearance of product (eSteth Digital Stethoscope) import worth Rs.5 Million.
- Tender filing & succeeding in bid (Govt. of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Health Department)
- Trained team on WEBOC & Custom Clearance issues for smooth Supply Chain operations.
- Spoke at a panel discussion conducted by doctHERs on Women Empowerment & use of Technology in Healthcare

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT OFFICER



Tech4Life Enterprises | Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Digital Health & Tele-medicine Firm

- Development & expansion of the distribution network (South Asia & Africa)
- Onboarding & Training of new distributors
- Customer Relationship Management
- Established working relationships with local startups in Healthcare & Technology: doctHErs.pk / Sehatkahani.pk / Marham.pk
- Lead Sales Team
- Copywriting & copyediting for Marketing Communication across all channels
- Completed Training for HIPAA Certification

CONFERENCES

- Secretary General IUMUN (2014)
- Secretary General Guards Public College MUN (2015)
- Model United Nations
 - IBA Karachi
 - City School (PAF)
 - Bahria University

AWARDS

- City School (PAF) '12
 - Outstanding Diplomacy
- Igra University Model UN '12
 - Best Delegate
 - Outstanding Diplomacy

TEACHING

- Business Communication
- Business Law
- Economics
- Business English

REFERENCES

- Malik Muhammad Ahad (ex-Manager Marketing & Sales - Tech4Life Enterprises)
 - o **+92-322-397-9899**
- Masroor Durrani (Managing Director - Helios Pakistan)
 - o **+92-334-305-6694**
- Shadab Durrani (Cofounder
 - JetpackGo)
 - o +92-345-234-2948
- Uzma Waqas (ex-Marketing Manager Sindbad Pvt. Ltd.)
 - o +92-342-204-3980

COFOUNDER

JetpackGo.com.pk | Jan 2015 - Dec 2015



JetpackGo was a Digital Marketing & Growth-hacking agency incubated at IBA Aman Center for Entrepreneurship Development

- Growth Hacking, Digital Marketing & Web Development Services.
 - Telenor Myanmar (Business Strategy)
 - Raymond Apparel (Social Media Marketing)

ASSISTANT STRATEGIC PLANNER

Helios Pakistan | Oct 2013 - Dec 2014

Branding, Event Management

- Strategic planning & Marketing management of client projects
 - Shing Point (Launch of Shing Tech's retail outlets)
 - WWF Nature Carnival 2014 (50,000+ footfall)

MARKETING INTERN

Sindbad Wonderland | June 2012 - Jul 2012





• Cartoon Network collaboration for Birthday bash campaign

EDUCATION

MA (ECONOMICS)

University of Karachi (2017)

- Micro & Macro Economics
- Public Finance & Monetary Economics
- Islamic Economics

MBA (MARKETING)

3.3 CGPA

2nd Division

Igra University (2015)

- Research study (Attributes of Islamic Apparel brand)
- Tapal TVC & Radio advertisement
- Meal on Wheels Marketing Plan
- Cafedemia Brand Development
- Video: 7 Habits of Highly Effective People

BACHELOR OF COMMERCE

2nd Division

Govt. College of Commerce & Economics (2008)

INTERMEDIATE

B Grade

DA Degree College for Men (2006)

• Table Tennis Competition

MATRICULATION

A+ Grade

DA Shiekh Khalifa Bin Zayed High School (2004)

- Highschool Qirat group
- Inter-school Debate Competition

VOLUNTEERING

- Member Editorial Board PKKH.tv (2007-2010)
- Disaster Relief Camp Pakistan Army (2005)